Last Kind Words is a romance, drama, mystery film directed by Kevin Barker.
17-year old Eli moves with his family to the isolated farm of reclusive
Waylon, a man whose dark past threatens to overtake him.
Eli’s family works to restore the desolate fields, while
he becomes fascinated with the forests.
While on the farm, Eli meets the mysterious Amanda when she gives him an apple.
The next day she extracts a promise from him to avoid the deep woods.
Reeling from a violent encounter with his father, one night he breaks
this promise and finds her body hanging from a tree.
Waylon, played by Brad Dourif.
Eli, played by Spencer Daniels.
Amanda, played by Alexia Fast.
Ida, played by Marianne Hagan.
Katie, played by Sarah Steele.
Bud, played by Clay Wilcox.
A person's last words, their final articulated words stated prior to death or as death approaches, are often
recorded because of the decedent's fame, but sometimes because of interest in the statement itself.
(People dying of illness are frequently inarticulate at the end, and in such cases their actual last utterances may not be
recorded or considered very important.) Last words may be recorded accurately, or, for a variety of reasons, may not.
Reasons can include simple error or deliberate intent.
Even if reported wrongly, putative last words can constitute an important part of the perceived
historical records or demonstration of cultural attitudes toward death at the time.
Charles Darwin, for example, was reported to have disavowed his theory of
evolution in favor of traditional religious faith at his death.
This widely disseminated report served the interests of those
who opposed Darwin's theory on religious grounds.
However, the putative witness had not been at Darwin's deathbed
or seen him at any time near the end of his life.
Cultural traditions around the world ascribe special significance to words uttered at or near
death, but the form and content of reported last words may depend on cultural context.
There is a tradition in Hindu and Buddhist cultures of an expectation of a meaningful farewell statement; Zen
monks by long custom are expected to compose a poem on the spot and recite it with their last breath.
In Western culture particular attention has been paid to last words which demonstrate
deathbed salvation – the repentance of sins and affirmation of faith.
The tone is dark and emotional and mind_bending.